Hişar Kaya

London, Mobile: 074 9560 6727 Email: hisar.kaya@hesharp.co.uk

PROFILE

Highly proficient **FRONTEND DEVELOPER** interested in **CONTRACT ROLES** with 12+ years of experience building web-based applications for the government, financial sector and major SMEs using backend technologies such as ASP.Net C# and T-SQL and frontend technologies such as **JavaScript**, **HTML5**, **CSS3**. Experienced in the full life cycle of the delivery from analysis to development and **TDD** testing within the **SCRUM** practice.

EXPERTISE

Markup languages: HTML/HTML5, CSS3

Programming languages: JavaScript (ES5/ES2015+), C#

CSS frameworks and extension languages: Bootstrap, Sass/LESS, Flexbox

JavaScript frameworks and libraries: ReactJS/Redux, jQuery

Backend technologies: ASP.Net MVC/Web Forms, T-SQL

Development tools: Webpack, Git, Node Package Manager (NPM)

Test frameworks: MOCHA

Project management: XP, SCRUM

• Has ability to work under pressure and a hard-working and motivated professional

EXPERIENCE

<u>www.nmfs.uk</u> – New Moon Future Solutions Ltd, Watford, UK, 01/2017 – 02/2017 – **Frontend Developer, Self-employed**

- Working as contractor through my own company Hesharp LTD
- Building frontend designs using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript based on requirements
- Modernization and fixing the frontends of the existing web faced products.

www.sgk.gov.tr – Social Security Institution, Turkey, 04/2013 – 12/2016 – IT Specialist, Government

- Managed team of 3 developers for the design and development of official documents archiving functionality. As a SCRUM Master, responsible for implementation of product backlog, coordination of Sprints and arranging daily activities.
- A 3 tiered architecture- model, controller and presentation layers built using Object Orientation principles. A web front end with JavaScript, ReactJS, jQuery and Bootstrap and written in ASP.Net MVC linking to a back end tier.
- <u>Key achievement:</u> Forecasting **an increase on revenues by 316%** as a value of **1.2 billion dollars by 2018**

- Carried on the design and development of legal consultancy application as a full-stack developer using ASP.Net Web Forms and JavaScript, CSS, HTML. Responsible, end to end, for implementation of requirements, design and development processes and release tasks.
- Built a web service application interconnects related government departments using **WCF**.
- Key achievement: Decrease in stationary costs by 1 million dollars/year

www.ce.com.tr - Ce Technology, Turkey , 12/2003 - 12/2006 - Software Developer, ICT Business

- **Leaded** a team of 2 developers, 1 graphic designer and 1 customer service representative for the design and development of web sites using a built-in CMS system.
- Designed and developed a banking SMS functionality with pull and push services using T-SQL.
- <u>Key achievement:</u> **Trained and mentored** junior developers in **web technologies** resulting in significant productivity rate increases.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Successfully designed and developed an official e-notification of debts web application forecasting an increase on the number of informed companies and citizens from 30% to 95%. This will enable the government for 2018 to collect debts resulting more productive and a balanced budget for the department of Labor, again forecasting an increase on revenues by 316% as a value of 1.2 billion dollars.
- Trained and mentored junior developers in web technologies resulting in significant productivity rate increases and less time to deploy to production environment of applications. Increase in speed of development enabled ICT department to be more responsive to clients' requirements.
- **Developed and implemented** a web application for the Legal Consultancy Department, which reduced the usage of paper documents to aim paperless processes of the management tasks. This not only enabled the officers to become more productive also saves the costs and resulted in a measurable decrease in stationary costs by 1 million dollars/year.

EDUCATION

www.emu.edu.tr – Eastern Mediterranean University, Cyprus Faculty of Engineering – Computer Engineering, BSc. Sep 1997 - Jun 2001 (4 years)